KIRINOSHIMA MIDDLE SCHOOL
Our club's so demanding.
I was counting the days
till it was finally over.
You know who's cringe?
Miki. She didn't fit in at all.
- She took it way too seriously.
- I know.
But I was too scared to speak up.
Me too.
I wanted a new environment
where I could change myself.
TOP GRADES GUARANTEED
CRAM SCHOOL
I chose a cram school outside of my city
to get into
an academically competitive high school.
MIKI
I knew this would happen, but...
I don't know anyone here.
Everyone's already formed
their friend groups.
I've got to approach... No, I can't.
FRIEND GROUPS - GIRLS
TERRIFYING COMBINATION
They may act sweet and friendly
on the surface,
but they'll talk bad about me
behind my back.
GROAN
I'm tearing up just thinking about it.
It's turned into trauma.
I'm so lonely.
Hey, you here alone? Care if I sit by you?
- Who are you?
- Me?
My name's Minato Amamiya.
THE RAMPARTS OF ICE
EPISODE 3
3+(←)1
MEITEN HIGH SCHOOL
Hear me out.
Why does the upcoming exam cover so much?
Why didn't you start studying earlier?
This is off topic, but why are you back?
I forgot to grab my notebook.
I wanna study it today.
- The torture never ends!
- Sheesh.
A four-man study session.
It feels a little strange.
Listen, Miki. We broke up.
What? Again? When?
Two days ago.
What? That's super recent!
What happened? What'd you do?
Why do you assume it's my fault?
Well, you know...
LIVELY CHATTER
Should I be listening?
- She called me because she wanted to meet.
- What a personal thing to talk about...
Man, I'm always getting dumped.
That's what bothers you?
What? Didn't expect it?
Huh? No...
How do I put it?
Well, it's like...
when you just go through a break up,
I thought you're supposed
to be depressed or resentful.
Not at all.
On the contrary, I'm thankful
they liked me, even for a short time.
Capisce?
You hear this guy?
Gee.
Guess that's how some people see it.
- You think I'm a player, huh?
- He got me.
I may not look it, but I'm heartbroken.
Of course he is.
That was insensitive of me.
FEELING DOWN
Sorry, I guess.
Then, why don't you comfort me?
Okay, that's enough from you!
Minato, you're kinda like this.
Your grip!
Koyun, you can brush off
whatever Minato says.
- 'Kay.
- How come?
Miki?
Yota-sensei, so, about this part...
- Oops, there I go again.
- Ugh, again.
Yota, you klutz!
Klutz?
What am I gonna do with you?
Always dropping things.
Oh, shoot.
FLUSTER FLUSTER
UGH!
Here. Is that everything?
Thanks.
She laughs just like the rest of us.
Oh, well.
See ya. We're heading this way.
Don't want us to walk with you?
No thanks, but I appreciate the offer.
I'm with her.
It's time for my grip strength to shine!
Hey, it's actually really powerful.
You be careful too, Miki.
Bye, guys! Thanks again, Yota!
What about me? I helped you with English.
Thanks to you too.
Am I an afterthought?
Koyun! I want Dyna Potato by the station.
Can we stop by real quick?
DYNAMITE POTATO
I'm down, but what about dinner at home?
Don't worry! It'll be an appetizer.
Liar.
I've got a separate stomach for it.
Miki sure loves to chat.
She should be like that all the time.
What're you up to today, Yota?
Wiener dog!
I'll chomp on this
and head to the community center.
You're kidding.
It's gonna catch up with you someday.
Wanna have dinner at my place?
My mom's always happy to see you.
I'll pass. Thanks though.
See ya.
Don't overdo it.
I know.
With everything. I mean it.
Yota acts that way,
but as for her...
What's on her mind?
What if she has a crush on him?
I wouldn't go for Yota if I were you.
Wait for me!
Koyun, how long have you known Minato?
Huh? We only recently met.
It was a little before
we walked home together.
He approached me
at the bottom of the staircase, and...
What'd he say to you?
Huh?
What did he say?
Well, we really didn't talk about
anything important.
Sorry.
Koyun, you're kinda like this.
Well, then it's fine, I guess.
Miki...
Could it be that she...
I overslept.
I wanted to start walking
when no one's on their way to school.
That's at least half an hour earlier.
Early morning during the exam period,
that's when the path to school
becomes quiet for a change.
This kind of vibe...
For some reason, I like it.
Hikawa, do you usually
walk to school around this time?
- Huh?
- Morning.
Here I was, thinking I left a tad early.
That's admirable.
No...
I come much later
when it's not exam period.
And I planned
on leaving much earlier this morning.
Ugh, it'll take too long to explain.
Not at all.
Common interests...
Say, Hikawa,
do you know a guy named Igarashi?
Wait. What?
What did he say just now?
Igarashi?
Why'd you ask? Do you know him?
My soccer club has joint practice
with West High from time to time.
That's where I met him.
Were you friends with him? He might
recognize you if I told him your name.
No. We had no connection whatsoever.
He wouldn't recognize me
even if you told him my name.
I see.
Well, he's coming to our school, but
you wouldn't recognize each other then.
When is that?
It'll be during club activities
on the afternoon of the last day of exams.
Really.
I'm definitely leaving early.
Wait, if he's asking me about him, then...
Is Amamiya good friends with Igarashi?
Joint practice starts
right as the exams end.
- We're pullin' out all the stops.
- They even mentioned their middle schools.
West High's exams are also...
Oh, no. I can't pay attention
to what he's saying at all.
I brought questions
for last year's finals today.
Apparently, the test for subjects
like History barely changes.
What? How'd you get your hands on it?
Let's just say I asked
for a tiny favor from a senior.
You're coming to my classroom
after school again, right?
Well, later then.
BOW
Morning. It's been like, what, yesterday?
What do I even say?
He's not a shy one. He can talk to anyone.
STRONG COMMUNICATOR
Miki has a crush on...
No, it's only a guess at this point.
Miki looked clearly bothered
that me and Amamiya knew each other.
His connection with Igarashi
is worrisome too.
This might be a good time
for me to take a step back from it all.
SIGH
All I want is some peace.
Koyun and Minato...
This guy's Yota.
He's massive.
My younger brother's a tough one like me.
Yup. My cram school just ended.
Yup, I'm at the usual convenience store.
What're you worried about?
Wonder what sides everyone brought today.
Yeah, lookin' forward to lunch!
Hey Miki. Let's swap our sides.
Let's!
Hikawa.
It's good that
you're a serious student and all,
but you should at least
have some fun during lunch.
But the teacher's room is warm.
What are you? A cat?
Anyway, got a question for me?
You do it like this, and it becomes this.
That's how you get the answer.
That makes sense.
Now, be on your way. Go.
- Shoo.
- Tsk.
I'll go visit Noriko then.
Stop going room to room for the heater.
She stops by here often.
Yes, she does.
I've never seen her
hang out with the other students.
I'm concerned for her.
Perhaps she finds it easier
to speak to adults.
There's a clear distance
between a teacher and a student.
She knows there's a line you won't cross,
and that's why she feels at ease with you.
I want the students to be besties
and enjoy their youth together!
THE TEEN YEARS GO BY IN A FLASH!
Suwa-sensei, you should know
that forcing your good intentions
can end up hurting people.
Matsumoto, what happened to you?
Let's see. My paint set and sketchbook...
- Is that everything for today's class?
- I'm saying it for your own good.
- No, seriously.
- You gotta know your limits.
POKE OUT
Can I take your word for it?
It's Amamiya.
FLASHBACK
- Why did you ignore me?
- I'm reminded.
I need some distance.
No, wait.
He's surrounded by people I don't know.
Besides, he hasn't noticed me.
Remember, I need some distance!
This is fine. I'm not ignoring him.
I'll stay quiet
so he walks off without noticing.
No, he's looking right at me.
BOW
THE QUICK BOW AND DIP OUT STRATEGY
Hi.
YAY
Man, he's so expressive
with his movements.
HELLO THERE
- What is it?
- Stare.
STARE
Stop it! Make it stop!
Please, don't mind me!
Gimme a sec.
Wait. He's coming over!
There really isn't a need to do this.
What're you doing?
You should've just said hi.
There's no need to peek out.
But...
Before I forget.
Tell me your contact info.
Distance!
Thanks.
What's in that bag?
I'm headed to Art next, so...
I see.
Class 2's elective is Art.
What're you doing? Oil paint?
No, we're doing acrylic gouache right now.
Good luck!
Miki.
- Oops.
- What is it?
Sorry. Switching classrooms. Gotta go.
Time to get going!
WHOOSH
She was by herself again.
SMILE
WITH YOTA
Hey, Yota.
PHEW - TEEHEE - SMILE
WITH MINATO
I meant to stop by my locker.
Switching classrooms.
She acts way too differently between
the people she likes and everyone else.
EVERYONE ELSE
Heya.
You approached the Queen
like it's nothing.
You've got a heart of steel.
Well, I was hoping we could be friends.
But she ran away from me.
Now I'm sad.
As if you know what it's like to be sad.
- For real.
- Come on, that's rude.
Here they are. Last years' questions!
Minato, you're godly!
This will be my ticket
to ace the subjects heavy on memorization.
You're not in the position to relax yet.
Keep your guard up.
The last math test
had a super low average score,
so there's a chance it'll be fairly easy.
I hope that's the case.
And what was your score
on this test with a low average, Yota?
Say something!
Yota, you could've enrolled at East High.
They've got a decent basketball team too.
Why'd you pick Meiten?
Huh? Because I live close by.
That's why you chose this school?
And you're happy with that?
Come on,
he can't tell you that he deliberately
chose a school below his academic level
so he can rank near the top and aim
for a designated-school recommendation.
That's how it is.
Hey. Minato, it's really not like that.
Guess we're worlds apart.
Miki!
Koyun, you're locked in today.
Hey! You changed the subject.
Well, I wanted to get
some distractions off my mind.
What? Is something distracting you?
Yup. All sorts of things, actually.
Like I thought.
She acts totally different.
Hikawa, do you have a boyfriend?
What?
No, but...
Why's he asking all of a sudden?
Okay, then.
What is it?
What's the point of asking
something like that?
Do you know a guy named Igarashi?
Is Igarashi trying
to dig around through him?
No, I'm definitely overthinking it.
As if he'd get someone else to ask.
It was a long time ago.
He wouldn't take it this far.
Minato.
You can't aim for her, all right?
Is that what this is about?
Can't I have her, Father?
You won't date my daughter.
They're joking around.
See, I was just overthinking.
Self-conscious and paranoid...
I'm ashamed.
Wait. What about Miki?
Blank!
I can't get a good read
on what she's thinking.
What do I do?
I can't even tell what
my childhood friend's feeling.
I'm gonna replenish on sugar.
SUGAR
I'm gonna check out the vending machine.
I'll grab something
for Koyun and Yota too.
What about me?
- You get your own.
- Hey!
So, come with me.
Huh? Sure.
We'll be back soon.
Miki...
Hey, Miki. What was that about?
I read the manga
you told me about, Ishida.
See you later, Yoshino!
Yamashita! About that anime you mentioned.
- I watched it. It was good.
- You know,
Minato's such a social butterfly.
He's like that at school too.
Really.
I'm jealous. I wish I could be like him.
Apparently, Minato
can't help but intervene
when someone seems lonely.
- What?
- It's like he pities them.
Pities them?
Here, I'll pay.
I meant to buy Hikawa a drink anyway.
Why?
The other day, I tried
to talk to her here but it made her jump.
She ended up buying
a super weird drink on accident.
AUTHENTIC CURRY DRINK
That's the one.
I'd forgotten all about it until now.
Say, Minato...
What do you think of Koyun?
What?
Subtitle translation by: Megumi Hunter